<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Peter Wambua&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Peter Wambua&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 02:49:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>NeuroSync-D Sherlocks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/neurosync-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 02:49:05 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/neurosync-d/</guid>
      <description>NeuroSync-D Sherlocks Challenge This is a write-up about the challenge NeuroSync-D, which is part of the Sherlocks challenges in HackTheBox focused on improving learners&amp;rsquo; proficiency in blue team security. As a web pentester, I honestly love investigating web attacks. Feels just like home, and this challenge was no different&#xA;Description: NeuroSync™ is a leading suite of products focusing on developing cutting edge medical BCI devices, designed by the Korosaki Coorporaton. Recently, an APT group targeted them and was able to infiltrate their infrastructure and is now moving laterally to compromise more systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phantom Check</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/phantom-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 02:48:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/phantom-check/</guid>
      <description>Phantom Check Sherlocks Challenge This is a write-up about a challenge I did a while back, Phantom Check which is part of the Sherlocks challenges in HackTheBox. It tests your knowledge in investigating WMI logs. WMI is the infrastructure for management data and operations on Windows-based operating systems&#xA;Description: Talion suspects that the threat actor carried out anti-virtualization checks to avoid detection in sandboxed environments. Your task is to analyze the event logs and identify the specific techniques used for virtualization detection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Own Soc Lab</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/building-your-own-soc-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:04:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/building-your-own-soc-lab/</guid>
      <description>🧪 Build Your Own SOC Home Lab: Step-by-Step Guide ✅ Overview&#xA;This comprehensive guide of how I set up my SOC home lab, and I have written it to guide you through setting up a fully functional Security Operations Center (SOC) home lab, compatible with both VirtualBox and VMware Workstation. You&amp;rsquo;ll build a safe, isolated environment using Windows 10, Kali Linux, Sysmon, and Splunk to simulate real-world attacker–defender scenarios.&#xA;📑 Index Click any section below to jump to it:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tjctf2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/tjctf2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 04:38:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/tjctf2025/</guid>
      <description>TJCTF Web Challenges This is a walkthrough of some interesting web challenges that I tackled the TJCTF 2025 together with my team, fr334aks-mini&#xA;Loopy Can you access the admin page? Running on port 5000&#xA;For this challenge, we are given a website that shows other website HTML content previews. Trying https://thecyberlearner.github.io: We are told to access the admin site on port 5000, so I definitely knew I&amp;rsquo;m dealing with an SSRF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Himaya</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/himaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 15:56:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/himaya/</guid>
      <description>Himaya We are the Hushed Protector of Health Data</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>jscalc HackTheBox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/jscalc-htb/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 04:29:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/jscalc-htb/</guid>
      <description>HTB web challenge jscalc walkthrough</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Secret Sanctum Walkthrough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/the-secret-sanctum-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 05:52:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/the-secret-sanctum-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>This is a walkthrough of a simple web challenge I created for CyberKimathi CTF competition.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Airplane THM Walkthrough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/airplane-thm-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 07:17:09 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/airplane-thm-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>A walkthrough of a medium room in TryHackMe. A great room needing critical thinking to exploit path traversal attacks to scripting to manipulate a gdbserver process to a tricky privilege escalation by ruby.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daystar Hackathon CTF</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/daystar-hackathon-ctf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:47:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/daystar-hackathon-ctf/</guid>
      <description>Daystar Hackathon CTF writeups My team CyberKimathi participated in the hackathon held at Daystar University. Being just a 2 hrs CTF and to be determined by time, we solved a couple of challenges, toping the competition. Here is a writeup of some:&#xA;Challenge 1: Threat Intelligence&#xA;A Malicious actor has been using the IP 64.176.194.7 to spread malware, can you identify the filename to the Powershell script used in the malicious activity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Logjammer Sherlocks Walkthrough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/logjammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 01:12:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/logjammer/</guid>
      <description>This challenge is part of the Sherlocks HackTheBox challenges which are mainly focused on improving your defensive skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A SOC Odyssey - Windows Event IDs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/windows-event-ids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 05:38:22 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/windows-event-ids/</guid>
      <description>A module from CTFROOM focusing on Windows Event IDs, and aiming to test your understanding of Windows Event IDs and their use in incident response.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Pentest Report</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-pentest-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 01:29:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my-first-pentest-report/</guid>
      <description>A writeup of the first Penetration Testing Report I wrote for my project in a penetration testing course</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kioptrix Level 1 Walkthrough</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/kioptrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 03:21:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/kioptrix/</guid>
      <description>Kioptrix is usually the starting point of all penetration testers, the first box we pawn. Here is a walkthrough of how I rooted my kioptrix box.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Pentesting with AIRCRACK-NG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/wirelesspentesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 02:11:40 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/wirelesspentesting/</guid>
      <description>Perfoming Wireless Penetration Testing with AIRCRACK-NG This is a walkthrough of how to crack WPA/WPA2 WiFi router password in some minutes. Note this is only for educational purposes, hence do not attack a network that isn’t yours or one without permission to.&#xA;Just being a campus student, I really don’t have an external wireless adapter but it is crucial as it gives you a faster, more reliable connection to your available network signals through the USB port instead.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
